# **OWEN MORGAN-JONES**

owen.morganjones@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/owenmorganjones/

Software engineering lead based in Glasgow, Scotland, with over 15 years experience in design, development, Agile delivery and support of many full stack web applications. Extensive experience in all stages of the Software Development Life Cycle, including via DevOps methods. A proven record of bringing innovative solutions and new technologies to developments to improve delivery and user experience. Experienced in multiple languages, platforms, with certifications in AWS.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Expert to intermediate level knowledge of predominantly .Net based back end technologies, including C#, SQL Server, WebAPI, MVC, NHibernate, and EntityFramework.
- Over 8 years experience of delivering multi-million pound projects using agile methods.
- Formal certification as Amazon Web Services (AWS) cloud practitioner and extensive experience using Microsoft Azure DevOps (ADO).
- Robust experience of applying engineering patterns and practises in front end technologies.
- Experience of Domain Driven Design (DDD) and Test Driven Design (TDD) across the complete software development stack
- Experience of rapidly iterating on projects using DevOps methods and infrastructure-as-code, including deployment using Docker containers to AWS.
- Expert to intermediate level knowledge of common software development project management tools, including Visual Studio, Git, SVN, Jira, Trello, GitLab, Github and Sharepoint.
- Experience and comfort in working with both distributed and co-located teams.

# QUALIFICATIONS

- MEng (Hons) Software Engineering, Swansea University, 2005
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner 2020
- AWS Certified Associate Developer 2020

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **LEIDOS (FORMERLY LOCKHEED MARTIN)**

**FULL STACK DEVELOPER** 

Nov 2020 – Present

Various Public Sector Projects

Full Stack developer in a distributed team across a number of public sector projects delivering highly secure solutions utilising a number of technology platforms. These included delivering a zero-data-loss data access system that made use of AWS cloud technologies including S<sub>3</sub>, SQS, EC<sub>2</sub>, CodeCommit, and EKS.

Delivery was implemented using a rapid iteration DevOps method where the application was implemented on a number of Docker containers deployed in a Blue/Green manner with extensive use of infrastructure-as-code.

#### **UITECHNICAL LEAD**

Mar 2019 – Mar 2020 Subsea7 iTech Project

UI Technical Lead in a distributed team, delivering a rich, imagery intensive productive application for automated undersea pipeline analysis. Use of VueJS & ES6 with a surrounding toolchain including Maven, WebPack, and ESLint to deliver a highly modular front end application that is capable of being updated over satellite internet link only including deltas to updated modules.

Delivery was agile, with a sprint cycle of 3 weeks, featuring regular engagement with SMEs and users, which ensured a more optimised UI design allowing for highly productive keyboard control of an expert system.

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Jul 2018 – Mar 2019 CSAS Project

Full stack developer in a highly agile co-located team, with tight integration with the customer through Discovery, Alpha and Beta phases. The product was a Single Page Application front end in VueJS and Typescript that communicated with a Microservice based back-end written in C# via REST APIs, and integrated with SharePoint and DynamicsCRM. The solution was hosted on MS Azure cloud infrastructure and delivered using the MS ADO platform.

#### **TEAM LEAD AND DEVELOPER**

Mar 2015 – Dec 2017 AIB CIS Project

Led one team in a mutli-workstream programme delivering public and internal facing line of business applications for the Scottish Accountant in Bankruptcy. The main technologies used were ASP.NET MVC, NHibernate, and the application was designed using DDD principles. Also introduced a major reimplementation of the Data Warehouse integration that greatly improved the performance and user experience related to reporting.

#### **BRIDGEALL**

#### **SENIOR DEVELOPER**

Mar 2014 – Mar 2015 Various Projects

Team lead on a number of projects for public sector customers, all using delivery to the MS Azure cloud platform and taking advantage of DevOps methods and infrastructure-as-code.

# LOCKHEED MARTIN/AMOR GROUP

#### **SENIOR DEVELOPER**

Jan 2019 – Mar 2014

Process Safety KPI Dashboard Project

Extensive design and development work on a KPI Dashboard that used Big Data methodologies to Extract, Transform & Load data from multiple operational systems and present end users

with a KPI dashboard for a business-wide view onto process safety throughout their business and presenting those KPIs in a number of innovative real time reports.

# CONSCIA ENTERPRISE SYSTEMS LTD/INNOVATION DIGITAL LTD/CHUNK IDEAS LTD

#### **DEVELOPER**

Oct 2005 – Jan 2010

Developer across a number of line of business and public facing web applications.

# **OTHER KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Being amongst the first in Leidos to begin the transition to reactive web UIs via the use of KnockoutJS;
- Regular developments to internal reference architectures integrating new and improved technologies;
- Contribution to the open source library AutoMapper, adding improvements which are now used in tens of millions of projects worldwide.

# **CONTACT**

- Professional enquiries via LinkedIn.
- Referees available on request.

# **SOCIALS**

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/owenmorganjones/
- Github: https://github.com/Sharkwald